L. Patrick Gray III Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
- Legal File, 1955-1981 (Box 21-53)
  - Civil lawsuits (Box 21)
    - Anderson v. Nixon, 1977-1978 (Box 21)
    - Bohmer v. Nixon, 1975-1977, (2 folders) (Box 21)
    - Driver v. Helms, 1975-1978 (Box 21)
    - Gray v. Bell (Box 22)
      - 1980-1981, (7 folders) (Box 22)
      - 1982, (1 folder) (Box 22)
      - 1982, (2 folders) (Box 23)
      - 1983-1984, (3 folders) (Box 23)
    - Jabara v. Kelley, 1975-1979 (Box 23)
    - Kasanicky v. Kelley, 1975-1977 (Box 23)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 23)
      - 1973-1976 (Box 23)
      - 1977-1985, (2 folders) (Box 24)
    - Monroe v. Gray, 1976-1977 (Box 24)
  - United States v. Gray (Box 24)
    - Arraignment, 1978 (Box 24)
    - Correspondence, miscellaneous, 1978-1980 (Box 24)
    - Correspondence with lawyers (Box 24)
      - 1976-1977, (2 folders) (Box 24)
      - 1978, (1 folder) (Box 24)
      - 1978, (3 folders) (Box 25)
      - 1979-1981, (3 folders) (Box 25)
    - Discovery documents, 1955-1981 See also Classified, (2 folders) (Box 25)
    - Discovery documents, 1955-1981 See also Classified, (6 folders) (Box 26)
    - Discovery documents, 1955-1981, (1 folder) (Box 27)
    - Exhibits, 1979 (Box 27)
      - General (Box 27)
        - Vol. 1, (3 folders) (Box 27)
        - Vol. 2 (Box 27)
      - Gray notes on executive conferences (Box 27)
      - Terrorism (Box 27)
    - Federal grand jury, 1976-1977 See Closed (Box 27)
    - Indictment, 1978 (Box 27)
    - Interviews, 1979-1980 See also Classified, (3 folders) (Box 28)
    - Miscellaneous documents, 1971-1980, (5 folders) (Box 28)
    - Miscellaneous documents, 1971-1980, (2 folders) (Box 29)
    - Motions, memoranda, and related material (Box 29)
      - 1978, (3 folders) (Box 29)
      - 1978, (2 folders) (Box 30)
      - 1979 See also Classified, (2 folders) (Box 30)
      - 1980, (2 folders) (Box 30)
      - 1980, (2 folders) (Box 31)
      - 1981 (Box 31)
    - Navy records, 1978, (2 folders) (Box 31)
    - Notes (Box 31)
      - Discovery material review, 1978-1979, (4 folders) (Box 31)
      - Legal pads, 1978-1979, (3 folders) (Box 32)
      - Miscellaneous, 1976-1981 See also Classified, (2 folders) (Box 32)
      - Telephone calls (Box 32)
        - 1976-1977 (Box 32)
        - 1978-1981, (7 folders) (Box 33)
    - Pamphlet, 1979 (Box 33)
    - Press clippings (Box 33)
      - 1976-1977, (2 folders) (Box 33)
      - 1978, (1 folder) (Box 33)
      - 1978, (1 folder) (Box 34)
      - 1979-1981, (4 folders) (Box 34)
    - Proposed character witnesses, 1978 (Box 34)
    - Statement, 1980 (Box 34)
    - Summaries for lawyer, 1976 See also Classified (Box 34)
    - Trial material, 1972-1979, (1 folder) (Box 34)
    - Trial material, 1972-1979, (5 folders) (Box 35)
    - Trial material, 1972-1979, (2 folders) (Box 36)
  - United States v. Osorio, 1971-1973 (Box 36)
  - Watergate Affair (Box 36)
    - Confirmation hearings testimony, circa 1973-circa 1974, (3 folders) (Box 36)
    - Congress (Box 37)
      - House Committee on Armed Services Special Subcommittee on Intelligence (Nedzi Committee), 1972-1975 See also Classified, (7 folders) (Box 37)
      - Senate Committee on Appropriations Subcommittee (McClellan Committee), 1973 See also Classified (Box 38)
      - Senate Select Committee on Presidential Campaign Activities hearings (Ervin Committee) (Box 38)
        - Exhibits, 1972-1976 (Box 38)
          - Index (Box 38)
          - Nos. 1-26 (Box 38)
          - Nos. 27-55 (Box 38)
          - Nos. 56-75 (Box 38)
          - Nos. 76-89 (Box 38)
          - Nos. 90-109 (Box 39)
          - Nos. 110-129 (Box 39)
          - Nos. 130-150 (Box 39)
          - Nos. 151-165 (Box 39)
          - Nos. 166-179 (Box 39)
          - Nos. 180-195 (Box 39)
          - Nos. 196-219 (Box 39)
          - Nos. 220-224 (Box 39)
        - Interview, 1973 (Box 40)
        - Miscellany, 1974 (Box 40)
        - Notes, 1973, 1979 (Box 40)
        - Other witnesses, 1973 (Box 40)
          - Dean, John W. (Box 40)
          - Ehrlichman, John (Box 40)
          - Miscellaneous (Box 40)
        - Proposed statement exhibits, 1972-1973, (3 folders) (Box 41)
        - Statement, 1973 (Box 41)
          - As read (Box 41)
          - Drafts, (3 folders) (Box 41)
          - Drafts, (2 folders) (Box 42)
        - Testimony, 1973, (2 folders) (Box 42)
    - Correspondence with lawyer, 1973-1976, (3 folders) (Box 42)
    - Lawyer's files, Sachs, Stephen H. (Box 42)
      - Bates, Charles W., 1975 (Box 42)
      - Chronologies, 1973 (Box 42)
      - Confirmation hearings, 1973, (3 folders) (Box 43)
      - Correspondence and memoranda (Box 43)
        - 1973-1975, (5 folders) (Box 43)
        - 1976 (Box 44)
      - Dean, John W., statements and testimony, 1973 (Box 44)
      - Law, 1964-1974, (3 folders) (Box 44)
      - Miscellaneous documents, 1972-1973, (2 folders) (Box 44)
      - Miscellaneous documents, 1972-1973, (1 folder) (Box 45)
      - Notes, 1973-1975, (2 folders) (Box 45)
      - Opening statement, 1972-1973 (Box 45)
      - Presidential tapes, 1974 (Box 45)
      - "Twisting Slowly," 1974 (Box 45)
    - Miscellaneous documents, 1968-1973, (1 folder) (Box 45)
    - Miscellaneous documents, 1968-1973, (5 folders) (Box 46)
    - Notes (Box 46)
      - For lawyer, 1973-1979, (1 folder) (Box 46)
      - For lawyer, 1973-1979, (1 folder) (Box 47)
      - Miscellaneous, circa 1972-1979 (Box 47)
      - Telephone calls, 1973-1976, (3 folders) (Box 47)
    - Submission of Recorded Presidential Conversations to the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives by President Richard Nixon, April 30, 1974, 1974 (Box 47)
    - United States District Court for the District of Columbia (Box 48)
      - Grand jury 1973, 1973 See also Closed (Box 48)
      - Grand jury 1974, 1972-1976 See also Closed, (3 folders) (Box 48)
    - Watergate Special Prosecution Force (Box 48)
      - Documents, 1972-1974 (Box 48)
        - Sent to lawyer See also Classified, (4 folders) (Box 48)
        - Sent to lawyer, (4 folders) (Box 49)
        - Submitted to Jay Horowitz, 25 Mar. 1974, (4 folders) (Box 49)
        - Submitted to Jay Horowitz, 25 Mar. 1974, (8 folders) (Box 50)
        - Submitted to Jay Horowitz, 25 Mar. 1974, (2 folders) (Box 51)
      - International Telephone and Telegraph Corp. (ITT), 1971-1973, (4 folders) (Box 51)
      - Miscellany, 1974-1979 (Box 52)
      - Two files, 1973-1974, (2 folders) (Box 52)
      - Wiretap investigation (Box 52)
        - Lawyer's file, 1971-1975 See also Classified, (4 folders) (Box 52)
        - Miscellany, 1973-1975 (Box 53)
- Speeches and Writings, 1941-2008 (Box 53-70)
  The Speeches and Writings series features the writings, recordings, and resource material that Gray created and compiled for a book project he began in the 1970s and early 1980s but discontinued until the end of his life, when his son, Ed Gray, resumed work on the memoir. Ed Gray's files relating to In Nixon’s Web: A Year in the Crosshairs of Watergate, published three years after the death of L. Patrick Gray, are also part of this series. Copies of the speeches and remarks that Gray delivered while serving at the Department of Justice and the FBI are also filed here. Types of material include book drafts, memoir drafts, notes, transcripts, resource files, speeches, and digital files that include scanned documents, sound recordings, and video files.
  Arranged alphabetically by type of material and therein chronologically or numerically.
  - Article, 1954 (Box 53)
  - Book, In Nixon's Web (Box 53)
    - Correspondence, 2005-2008 (Box 53)
    - Drafts, 2007-2008 (Box 53)
      - Draft A, 2007 (Box 53)
      - Draft B, 2007 (Box 53)
      - Draft C, 2007 (Box 54)
      - Draft D, 2008 (Box 54)
      - Miscellaneous, 2007 (Box 54)
      - Miscellaneous, digital files, 2006-2007, mss86267_175_029
    - Miscellany, 2008 (Box 54)
    - Miscellany, book contract and other business documents, 2006, mss86267_175_029
    - Notes, Ed Gray, 2005-2007, (3 folders) (Box 55)
    - Notes, Ed Gray, planning notes, 2006, mss86267_175_011; mss86267_175_024
    - Proposal, 2006 (Box 55)
    - Proposal, 2005-2006, mss86267_175_024
    - Research, 2005-2007, (2 folders) (Box 55)
    - Research, correspondence, notes, 2006, mss86267_175_016; mss86267_175_024; mss86267_175_033
    - Resource material, 1972-2008, (1 folders) (Box 55)
    - Resource material, 1972-2008, (2 folders) (Box 56)
    - Resource material, document scans, sound recordings, video files, 1969-2005, mss86267_175_003; mss86267_175_004; mss86267_175_005; mss86267_175_014; mss86267_175_016; mss86267_175_023; mss86267_175_029; mss86267_175_034; mss86267_175_035; mss86267_175_036; mss86267_175_037
  - Book project (Box 56)
    - Correspondence and telephone calls (Box 56)
      - 1974-1978, (5 folders) (Box 56)
      - 1979, (1 folder) (Box 56)
      - 1979, (2 folders) (Box 57)
      - 1980-1984, (2 folders) (Box 57)
    - Drafts (Box 57)
      - 1974, (3 folders) (Box 57)
      - 1974, mss86267_175_007
      - 1980-1981, (6 folders) (Box 58)
    - Miscellany, 1978-1981 (Box 58)
    - Notes, 1974-1981 (Box 59)
    - Outline file, 1978-1980 (Box 59)
    - Proposal, 1980-1981, (2 folders) (Box 59)
    - Resource material (Box 59)
      - Miscellaneous documents, 1972-1980, (3 folders) (Box 59)
      - Miscellaneous documents, 1972-1980, (6 folders) (Box 60)
      - Miscellaneous documents, 1972-1980, (1 folder) (Box 61)
      - Numerical file, 1941-1981 (Box 61)
        - 1. Richard M. Nixon (Box 61)
        - 2. Donald Segretti (Box 61)
        - 3. Stephen H. Sachs letter regarding no prosecution for destruction of Hunt files and Francis J. Martin letter regarding no prosecution for wiretaps (Box 61)
        - 4. Proxmire, LPG has occupied office illegally (Box 61)
        - 5. Phones calls with Dean and Petersen regarding Hunt files (Box 61)
        - 6. James McCord (Box 61)
        - 7. Sen. Byrd, "Dean lied" (Box 61)
        - 8. Martha Mitchell (Box 61)
        - 9. Desk calendar sheets from Horrowitz envelope II (Jan. 1, 1973 to Apr. 29, 1973) (Box 61)
        - 10. Analysis of calls in director's daily logs for first visit of Stephen H. Sachs on May 5, 1973 (Box 61)
        - 11. LPG notes of Marco Island, Fla., Feb. 24, 1973 (Box 61)
        - 12. Early telephone calls with John Mitchell. May 23, May 25, May 30, May 31, June 1, June 2, 1972 (Box 61)
        - 13. Wiretap investigation telephone calls to and from Richard Kleindienst, telephone call to Edward Miller regarding terrorism, and green writing tablet (Box 61)
        - 14. Confirmation hearing questions by senators (Box 62)
        - 15. Stephen H. Sachs meeting with Senator Edward M. Kennedy, Jan. 23, 1974, regarding wiretapping (Box 62)
        - 16. Original notes of telephone calls to and from Ehrlichman on Apr. 15, 1973. Book material. Compare with his version (Box 62)
        - 17. Original notes regarding telephone calls with Henry Petersen regarding Hunt's two files. Presidential transcripts support my version. (Box 62)
        - 18. Telephone calls to and from Dean, President and Haldeman. Good material for book. (Box 62)
        - 19. Watergate grand jury, July 19 and July 20, 1973 See Closed (Box 62)
        - 20. Proposed outline, Ervin Committee statement (Box 62)
        - 21. News clips, July 12, 1974, report of House Judiciary Committee regarding impeachment also New York Times, Aug. 26, 1974, final report (Box 62)
        - 22. Watergate trial, news clips (Box 62)
        - 23. News clips, President resigns (Box 62)
        - 24. Ehrlichman testimony, Ervin Committee, July 24, July 25, July 26, 1973. Telephone call with (TCW) Gray, Mar. 6, 1973 (Box 62)
        - 25. Ogarrio and Dahlberg: Young Chenow excerpts from Bates's memo (Box 62)
        - 26. Bolz to Bates of Sept. 26, 1972, regarding Jack Anderson column on espionage report to Attorney General Mitchell (Box 62)
        - 27. Feb. 23, 1973 meeting regarding Watergate investigation (Box 62)
        - 28. Gebhardt to Baker of Mar. 2, 1973, regarding any leads agents not permitted to follow (Box 62)
        - 29. Early new clips, excerpts June 20 to Aug. 2, 1972, note of Apr. 26, 1973, to call Richard G. Kleindienst and ask why he did not tell me John W. Dean asked him for reports (Box 62)
        - 30. John Dean (Box 63)
        - 31. Jack Anderson columns (Box 63)
        - 32. Clarence M. Kelley (Box 63)
        - 33. William Safire columns (Box 63)
        - 34. Originals of Tabs B and C of my opening statements, confirmation hearings, public speeches and field office visits, increases in minority employment. (Box 63)
        - 35. Robert Waters columns (Box 63)
        - 36. Woodward and Bernstein (general), also "Deep Throat" (Box 63)
        - 37. CBS transcripts (Box 63)
        - 38. Articles on Gray (Box 63)
        - 39. New Yorker "Reflections, the Watergate Prosecutions" (Box 63)
        - 40. The Hearst Case, Special Agent in Charge (SAC) Charles W. Bates. General, SAC Charles W. Bates (Box 63)
        - 41. Mid-1971 meeting with John N. Mitchell regarding FBI (Box 63)
        - 42. Notes July 6, 1974, referring to exhibits (good material here) (Box 63)
        - 43. Testimony of Kleindienst and Petersen before Ervin subcommittee (Box 63)
        - 44. Notes of July 13, 1974. Read Jack Levine's letter to Herbert J. Miller, Jr. (Box 63)
        - 45. The story of Job, Sunday, May 7, 1972, Sunday, May 14, 1972 (Box 63)
        - 46. Charlotte Observer, Friday, June 8, 1973, regarding Chaplain McAlpine (Box 63)
        - 47. Notes of TCW David Kinley, May 1, 1973 (important) (Box 63)
        - 48. The Washington Post, Oct. 6, 1972, Alfred C. Baldwin III to Jack Nelson (Box 63)
        - 49. Bolz to Bates, July 18, 1972, regarding identification of G. Gordon Liddy (Box 63)
        - 50. Barbara Herwig's notes of her TCW Charlie Bates regarding Walters-Helms story published in Washington Post in May, 1973 (Box 63)
        - 51. Is disclosure of FBI investigation reports to counsel to President a crime? (Title III) (Box 63)
        - 52. Commendatory letters from AUSA Silbert regarding work of agents (Box 63)
        - 53. Q's and A's regarding defendants working for CIA, Hunt research on Kennedy (Box 63)
        - 54. John T. Elliff letter to attorney general, Watergate file available to senators (Box 63)
        - 55. Committee for the Re-election of the President (CREEP) attorneys at interview not Mardian (Box 63)
        - 56. Circumstances regarding identification of G. Gordon Liddy (Box 63)
        - 57. LPG memo to FBI regarding withdrawal of nomination, Apr. 10, 1973 (Box 63)
        - 58. Memo of Feb. 23, 1973, from supervisors of Watergate investigation. (cross reference to 27) (Box 63)
        - 59. Keith decision, Feet [Felt] to Gebhardt per LPG request (Box 63)
        - 60. Judith Hoback and Penny Gleason (Box 63)
        - 61. John P. Mohr (Box 63)
        - 62. Richard Helms, CIA House and Senate panel investigations (Box 63)
        - 63. Senate Select Committee on Intelligence (Box 63)
        - 64. Presidential wiretaps, 1969 (Box 64)
        - 65. Wiretaps, general (Box 64)
        - 66. Edward S. Miller (Box 64)
        - 67. Wiretap investigation, general (Box 64)
        - 68. Wiretaps, Wounded Knee (see also 140) (Box 64)
        - 69. Integrity (from Dr. Bob Faus), Dudley W. Butler letters, Frank and Elise Abell letter (Box 64)
        - 70. Lowell P. Weicker, Jr. (Box 64)
        - 71. Daniel Mack Armstrong III (Box 64)
        - 72. John P. Buscher to Senator McMathias (Box 64)
        - 73. Robert T. Nischwitz, legal attache, Mexico City, drugs (Box 64)
        - 74. Opinion, attorney general, Apr. 30, 1941, regarding investigative reports (Box 64)
        - 75. Katherine V. Greene, M.D. (Mrs. Victor L. Liszka) false chain, Medicare payments (Box 64)
        - 76. I.T.T. hearings, Kleindienst (Box 64)
        - 77. Hunt, motion to suppress (Box 64)
        - 78. Disclosure of form FD 302 (Box 64)
        - 79. Memos to Mr. Kinley, Q's & A's regarding confirmation hearings, Mar. 4, 1973 (Box 64)
        - 80. Constitutionality of Title III, wiretap statute (Box 64)
        - 81. Weather Underground Organization (WUO), W. R. Wannall and Donald E. Moore (Box 64)
        - 82. "The Missing CIA Man" (John Paisley) New York Times Magazine, Jan. 7, 1979 (Box 64)
        - 83. Time, Mar. 26, 1973, "The FBI in Politics" (Box 64)
        - 84. Gray's political biography (Box 64)
        - 85. Life, Oct. 13, 1972, "Shake-up at the FBI" (Box 64)
        - 86. Neil J. Welch (Box 64)
        - 87. J. Wallace LaPrade (Box 64)
        - 88. Griffin B. Bell, Department of Political Justice (Box 64)
        - 89. William E. Simon, "War on the FBI" (Box 64)
        - 90. William H. Webster (Box 64)
        - 91. "Carter Criticizes Intelligence Effort," New York Times, Nov. 23, 1978, page 1 (Box 64)
        - 92. Law Enforcement Intelligent Unit (LEIU) (Box 64)
        - 93. Committee for Public Justice paper regarding FBI budget by Walter Pincus (Box 64)
        - 94. Intelligence, guidelines, reorganizations, etc. (Box 64)
        - 95. Freedom of the press (Box 64)
        - 96. David W. Marston, U.S. Attorney, E.D. Pa. discharge (Box 64)
        - 97. Birch Bayh (Box 64)
        - 98. Edward W. Brooke (Box 65)
        - 99. Robert Byrd (Box 65)
        - 100. Herman Talmadge (Box 65)
        - 101. Dan Flood (Box 65)
        - 102. Terrorism (Box 65)
        - 103. James B. Adams (Box 65)
        - 104. Senatorial perquisites (Box 65)
        - 105. Telephone calls to Gray and from Gray, June 17, 1972 to June 19, 1972 (Box 65)
        - 106. Koreagate (Box 65)
        - 107. Andrew Young (Box 65)
        - 108. Martin Luther King (Box 65)
        - 109. Time, Jan. 15, 1973 "Tattletale Gray" - response (Box 65)
        - 110. Issues and answers papers (Box 65)
        - 111. News clips, Ervin select committee (Box 65)
        - 112. Military draft (Box 65)
        - 113. Richard G. Kleindienst and Louis Patrick Gray, III. hearings to be attorney general and deputy attorney general, Feb. 22 and Feb. 23, 1972 (Box 65)
        - 114. Case of Max I. Chastain (Box 65)
        - 115. Letter from special agents in Chicago Field Division (Box 65)
        - 116. Max Fisher luncheon, Detroit Free Press (Box 65)
        - 117. Agronsky "Evening Edition" with Jack Anderson, Congressman Frank Denholm of South Dakota (Box 65)
        - 118. Congressmen Robert McClory, Don Edwards and Samuel L. Devine (Box 65)
        - 119. J. Edgar Hoover (Box 65)
        - 120. CIA mail cover operation (Box 65)
        - 121. Letters to former SAC Faisst and Deane Avery (not sent) (Box 66)
        - 122. Princeton conference on FBI (Box 66)
        - 123. Erwin N. Griswold (Box 66)
        - 124. Henry E. Peterson (Box 66)
        - 125. My memo regarding Brennan, my memo regarding Vesco Papers, notes regarding Bureau of Narcotics and Dangerous Drugs (BNDD) (Box 66)
        - 126. Earl J. Silbert, "District Lawyer" of April/May 1979, Volume 3 Number 5 (Box 66)
        - 127. Leon Jaworski (Box 66)
        - 128. FBI annual report, 1972 (fiscal year) (Box 66)
        - 129. Al Rosen to Marjorie Neenan, May 10, 1972, enclosing letters from assistant directors (Box 66)
        - 130. Dwight Dalbey (Box 66)
        - 131. Special Agent in Command (SAC) lists (Box 66)
        - 132. Events & issues, Department of Justice request for info to assist President in campaign trips, Thomas E. Bishop (Box 66)
        - 133. Health, Education, and Welfare Department (HEW) speech (Box 66)
        - 134. "The FBI File," Sanford Ungar, the Atlantic Monthly, April, 1975 (Box 66)
        - 135. Lloyd Shearer (Box 66)
        - 136. Richard G. Kleindienst (Box 66)
        - 137. House Select Committee on Intelligence (Box 66)
        - 138. William Colby, CIA and KGB (Box 66)
        - 139. Rockefeller report on CIA (Box 66)
        - 140. Wounded Knee (Box 66)
        - 141. William C. Sullivan (Box 66)
        - 142. Bag jobs (Box 66)
        - 143. John J. Sirica (Box 66)
        - 144. James Earl Carter (Box 66)
        - 145. John N. Mitchell (Box 66)
        - 146. John B. Connally (Box 66)
        - 147. Ellsberg burglary, psychiatrist's office (Box 66)
        - 148. Political corruption, general and individuals (Box 66)
        - 149. Policy of destroying FBI files (Box 66)
        - 150. Active FBI agent indicted (Box 66)
        - 151. House and Senate ethics bill (Box 66)
        - 152. Grand jury system (Box 66)
        - 153. LPG call to MacGregor, Nedzi subcommittee (Box 66)
        - 154. W. Mark Felt (Box 66)
        - 155. FBI miscellaneous (Box 66)
        - 156. Lancegate (Box 67)
        - 157. Benjamin R. Civiletti (cross-reference to 96) (Box 67)
        - 158. Organized crime (Box 67)
        - 159. Black Panthers (Box 67)
        - 160. Middle East (Box 67)
        - 161. ITT, Chile (Box 67)
        - 162. Gag order upset on CIA documents, CIA news leaks (Box 67)
        - 163. Maurice H. Stans (Box 67)
        - 164. FBI administrative action, Weatherman (Box 67)
        - 165. Dr. Peter G. Bourne (Box 67)
        - 166. Notes of Aug. 24, 1974, review of clippings (good material) (Box 67)
        - 167. "CIA Resisted White House Cover-up," Washington Post, May 16, 1973, LPG notes, May 16, 1973 (Box 67)
        - 168. Robert McNamara, Roswell L. Gilpatric (Box 67)
        - 169. Archibald Cox (Box 67)
        - 170. LPG letter to President and attorney general regarding withdrawal of nomination and resignation (Box 67)
    - Tapes (Box 67)
      - Indexes, 1980 (Box 67)
      - Recordings, 1978-1979, mss86267_175_017; mss86267_175_018; mss86267_175_019; mss86267_175_020; mss86267_175_021; mss86267_175_024
      - Transcriptions (Box 67)
        - 1978 (Box 67)
        - 1979, (4 folders) (Box 67)
        - 1979, (4 folders) (Box 68)
        - 1980, (3 folders) (Box 68)
  - Speeches and remarks (Box 69)
    - 1969-1973, (10 folders) (Box 69)
    - 1982-1985, 1998, (4 folders) (Box 70)
  - Unidentified draft, incomplete, undated (Box 70)
- Alphabetical File, 1936-2008 (Box 70-101)
  The Alphabetical File series contains material pertaining to other phases of Gray’s life, including his twenty-year career in the United States Navy, his tenure as executive assistant to the secretary of the Department of Health, Education, and Welfare and as assistant attorney general for the Civil Division at the Department of Justice, and his private legal practice. Types of material include correspondence, memoranda, appointment books, certificates, printed matter, photographs, a scrapbook and other memorabilia, and digital files.
  Arranged alphabetically by topic, name, or type of material and therein chronologically or in reverse chronological order.
  - Addresses, 1960s, 1971-1973, (2 folders) (Box 70)
  - Appointment books, calendars, and logbooks (Box 71)
    - 1971, (4 folders) (Box 71)
    - 1972, (1 folder) (Box 71)
    - 1972, (5 folders) (Box 72)
    - 1973-1974, (5 folders) (Box 73)
    - 2005 (Box 74)
  - Bar examination, Conn., 1958 (Box 74)
  - Biographical information, circa 1960-2006, (2 folders) (Box 74)
  - Central Intelligence Agency, general, 1974-1981 (Box 74)
  - Death, 2005 (Box 74)
    - Condolences, (2 folders) (Box 74)
    - Miscellany (Box 74)
    - Obituaries (Box 74)
  - Federal Bureau of Investigation (Box 74)
    - 1972-1975, (2 folders) (Box 74)
    - 1972-1975, (5 folders) (Box 75)
    - 1976, (2 folders) (Box 75)
    - 1977-1980, 2005, (3 folders) (Box 76)
  - Felt, W. Mark, revealed as "Deep Throat," 2005-2007, (3 folders) (Box 76)
  - Felt, W. Mark, revealed as "Deep Throat," correspondence, sound recordings, video file, 2005, mss86267_175_001; mss86267_175_014; mss86267_175_016; mss86267_175_023
  - Health, Education, and Welfare Department, 1969-1970, (3 folders) (Box 76)